[
    {
        "question": "Full form of INSAT",
        "options": [
            "Indian National Satellite",
            "Indian Nuclear Satellite",
            "International Nuclear Satellite"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Prithvi could travel a distance of ............... km due to the nuclear ballistic missile.",
        "options": [
            "170-300",
            "150-300",
            "200-300",
            "150-310"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Through ............... , Public Primary Health Centres in villages have been connected with super specialtyhospitals.",
        "options": [
            "INSAT",
            "NCSR",
            "APPLE",
            "BHASKAR - 1"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "More than ............... oil wells and ............... natural gas wells dug in the Bombay High Area.",
        "options": [
            "8400,33",
            "8500,33",
            "8400,34",
            "8500, 34"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The first Diesel engine was manufactured at the ............... at Varanasi.",
        "options": [
            "Chittaranjan Locomotive Works",
            "Diesel Locomotive Works"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Full Form of APPLE",
        "options": [
            "Airplane passenger Payload Experiment",
            "Ariane Passenger Payload Experiment",
            "Ariane Payload Passenger Experiment"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Director of the Bhabha Atomic Research Centre ?",
        "options": [
            "Dr. Raja Ramanna",
            "Dr. Homi Sethna",
            "Dr. Homi Bhabha",
            "Dr. A.P.J Abdul Kalam"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "India successfully performed her first nuclear test at Pokharan in Rajasthan on ............... .",
        "options": [
            "18 May 1975",
            "18 May 1974",
            "17 May 1974",
            "17 May 1975"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "When was Apple launched?",
        "options": [
            "19 June , 1981",
            "19 June, 1982",
            "19 July, 1981",
            "19 July, 1982"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Heavy Water Projects later named as?",
        "options": [
            "Heavy Water Activity",
            "Heavy Water Institution",
            "Heavy Water Department",
            "Heavy Water Board"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "Who took the decision of carrying out a �Nuclear Explosion�",
        "options": [
            "Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Prime Minister Indira Gandhi",
            "Dr. A. P. J Abdul Kalam",
            "Dr. Raja Ramanna"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Answer in one word: Who held the distinction of being the main internet service provider in India?",
        "options": [
            "VSNL",
            "BSNL", 
            "ISD",
            "MTNL"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Full Form of ISRO?",
        "options": [
            "Indian Space Recovery Organisation",
            "Indian Satellite Research Organisation",
            "Indian Space Research Organisation"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "............... is celebrated as �Science Day�.",
        "options": [
            "28 February",
            "28 March",
            "28 January",
            "28 April"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "When was Indian Space Research Organisation established?",
        "options": [
            "15 august 1990",
            "15 august 1969",
            "14 august 1969",
            "15 august 1969"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The contribution of ............... In the field of telecommunication service is significant.",
        "options": [
            "VSNL",
            "BSNL",
            "Sam Pitroda",
            "MTNL"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Full form of NPCIL",
        "options": [
            "Nuclear Power Corporation of India Ltd.",
            "Nuclear Point Corporation of India Ltd.",
            "New Power Corporation of India Ltd.",
            "Nuclear Power Company of India Ltd."
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False and If False, rewrite the correct sentence. NPCIL was set up in 1988 to generate electricity from atomic energy.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "What was one of them tests done called?",
        "options": [
            "Hydrogen Bomb",
            "Oxygen Bomb",
            "Hydrogen test",
            "Oxygen Test"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "What made easy to train scientists and technicians in setting up and running an earth station within thecountry and in which year?",
        "options": [
            "Telex Service,1963",
            "Domestic satellite communication earth station,1967",
            "International telecommunication service,1970",
            "ISD,1972"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    }
]